字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
but secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
为了阻止邪恶极速者萨维塔
In an attempt to stop the evil speedster Savitar,
我不小心闯入了未来
I was accidentally thrust into the future,
看到他杀死了我心爱的女人
and I saw him murder the woman that I love.
但是我不会再让这事发生了
But I won't let that happen.
我会尽我一切的努力
I'm gonna do everything in my power
来改变未来
to change the future,
而我是唯一来得及
and I'm the only one fast enough
拯救她的人
to keep her alive.
我就是  闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash."
我自由了
I'm free!
你是谁
Who are you?
我是未来的闪电侠
I am the future Flash.
我的余生不能拿来担心
I can't spend the rest of my life
我会不会成为冰霜杀手
wondering if I'm gonna become Killer Frost.
我明白你邀我加入团队的真正原因
I understand the real reason that you invited me on this team.
你只想让你的私人超能力者专家
You just want your own meta-human specialist
想办法给你找到解药
to try and find you a cure.
不只是因为这个
That's not the only reason.
真希望我能相信
I wish I could believe that.
对了  我叫西斯科  你就是吉普赛
I'm Cisco, by the way. You must be Gypsy.
你喜欢我
You're into me.
哪怕我曾经喜欢过  你也搞不定我
Even if I was, you couldn't handle me.
我会把那姑娘娶回家
I'll marry that woman.
爱瑞丝·韦斯特  你愿意嫁给我吗
Iris West, will you marry me?
愿意
Yes.
斯塔格工业
看来我们要找新工作了
Looks like we may need to find a new job.
听说斯塔格工业要被人收购了
Heard Stagg Industries may be getting bought out.
谁要收购
By who?
现在已经不重要了  对吧
Doesn't really matter now, does it?
反正我就知道这里有价值上百万的
All I know is we got millions of dollars of tech--
科技产品
like whatever that thing is--
却没人用
that no one's using.
那我很确定如果我拿走几样
Then surely you gentlemen won't mind
你们也不介意
if I abscond with some of it.
特别是这一个
This piece in particular.
你怎么进来的
How did you get in here?
相信我  这招太简单了
Believe me, that's the least impressive of my tricks.
举起手来  伙计  否则我要开枪了
Hands up, pal. Do it now, or I'll shoot.
站住
Stop!
他怎么做到的
How the hell did he do that?
或许你们能想出我是怎么做到的
Maybe you can figure out how I did it,
不过  我觉得你们没有时间了
but... I doubt you'll have time.
闪电侠
第三季
第十八集
太漂亮了
It's just beautiful.
跟你炯炯有神的大眼很相配
You know what, it matches the sparkle in your eyes.
-谢谢  -巴里
- Thank you. - Barry,
你祖父对珠宝的品味相当高
your grandfather had really good taste in jewelry.
没错
Yeah, he did.
好了  详细说说  当时什么情况
Okay, so, break it down. How did it happen?
我们当时在家里
We were at the apartment,
然后  巴里给我唱了首歌
and, Barry sang to me.
然后他就求婚了
And then he proposed.
天哪  太浪漫了
Oh, my God, that's so romantic.
你还会唱歌
You sing?
不如乔唱得好
Not as good as Joe.
别闹了  巴里
Shut up, Barry.
我差点忘了
Well, okay, that reminds me,
我妹妹有四张《汉密尔顿》音乐剧的票
my sister has four tickets that she can't use...
-她去不了了  -《汉密尔顿》
- to "Hamilton." - "Hamilton"?
免费的票
On the house.
我想如果你们有兴趣的话
I thought that maybe we could make it a double
我们也许可以来个四人约会
if you guys were interested?
我们感兴趣  什么时候
Uh, yeah, we're interested. When?
七月的第一个周末
First weekend in July.
七月
Um, July.
你们俩那时没空吗
Y-- does that not work for you guys?
不  完全有空
No, that works great.
我们都会去的
We'll be there, all of us.
别  别这么做
Don't! Don't do this!
拜托  我求你了
Please? I'm begging you! Just--
巴里
Barry!
你输了  巴里
You lose, Barry.
不
No!
一切还是一样的
Well, everything's the same.
未来没有改变
The future has not changed.
好吧  我们有两个月的时间
All right. Well, we have two months
确保能改变未来
to make sure that it does.
我们应该用处理其他问题的方法
Okay, well, we should approach this
来处理这个问题
the same way we approach any other problem--
从我们知道的开始入手
start with what we know.
如果不理解问题  就无法解决问题
Problem can't be solved if it's not understood.
难就难在这里
Therein lies the rub.
我觉得在问题发生之前
I feel like we can't understand any of this
我们完全无法理解
until it actually happens.
就像萨维塔的预言
It's like Savitar's prophecies.
没错  还有报纸的头条
Precisely, and just like the newspaper headlines.
乔·韦斯特队长
在市政厅授勋
冰霜杀手仍然逍遥法外
萨维塔
除了一点
Well, all bar one.
有罪案发生  我们得走了
It's a crime scene. We gotta go.
-斯塔格工业  -糟了
- Stagg Industries? - All right, no.
朱利安  在你走之前
Hey, Julian, before you go,
有个中城剧院
there was an envelope delivered for you
寄给你的信封
from the Central City Opera.
你之前说你从来没去过  所以...
Yes, you'd mentioned that you'd never gone before, so--
前阵子我给我俩买的  但是现在
well, I got them for us a while back, but now--
你和别人一起去吧
just go with whoever you'd like.
看来你和朱利安之间
Looks like things between you and Julian
有点冷若冰霜啊
are a little frosty, huh?
现在说冰霜双关语还太早吧
It's too soon for the cold puns?
-对  -我想也是
- Yeah. - Yeah. Thought so.
我之前拿了一块魔法石
He still doesn't trust me after I lied
却没坦白  他现在还是无法相信我
about taking a piece of the Philosopher's Stone.
为了去除你的超能力
You did what you felt you needed to do
你做了你认为必要的事
to get rid of your powers.
你我都清楚这点  但是他...
I know that and you know that, but he--
他会想明白的  等着吧
He'll come around. Watch.
我不知道他会不会  西斯科
I don't know that he will, Cisco.
小巴  有发现吗
Hey, Bar. Anything?
还没有
Nothing yet.
这东西怎么会灌满水
How the hell did this thing get filled with water
这些可怜人怎么会被困在里面
and those poor dudes get trapped in here?
难住我了
Beats me.
整个箱子也没有水渗入
There's no water access in the entire wing.
每层楼都装有卤代烷气体灭火系统
Instead of sprinklers,
没有消防喷洒  如果起火
every floor uses a halon gas system
灭火系统会吸收所有氧气
that absorbs all the oxygen if there's a fire.
那安全监控录像呢
What about the security cams?
也没有装
None of them either.
显然斯塔格的天才们
Apparently, the Stagg geniuses
不想他们的秘密泄露出去
don't want any of their "Secrets" to get out.
朱利安  请告诉你有所发现
Julian, please tell me you found something.
暂时没有  警探
Nothing yet, Detective.
没有指纹  没有DNA
No fingerprints, no DNA,
只有两具肿胀的尸体
just two rather plump looking corpses.
被盗的技术呢
What about the stolen tech?
也没发现  完全没人提起
Nothing. No one's saying a thing.
每个人对此事都守口如瓶
Everyone is incredibly tight-lipped about it.
当然了  我去打几个电话
Of course they are. Look, I'll make some phone calls,
看看能不能撬开他们的嘴
see if I can pry those lips open, all right?
好  我会继续调查
Okay. I'll keep working on it.
这是现在我们最不需要处理的事情
This is the last thing we need to be dealing with right now.
我也觉得  但是我们不能无所事事
I feel the same way, but we can't just do nothing.
爱瑞丝不会放过我们的
Iris ain't gonna let us get away with that.
我懂  乔  但是我们快没时间了
I know, Joe, but we're running out of time.
所以你我要迅速了结这个案子
That's why you and me need to solve this case fast.
是
Yeah.
有时  我希望你没告诉我未来会怎样
Sometimes...I wish you hadn't told me what was gonna happen.
我懂
Yeah, I know.
等等
Hold on.
什么事
What's up.
看样子科德工业正在发生一起抢劫案
Looks like we got a robbery in progress over at Kord Industries.
好  谢了  现在又是科德工业
Great, thanks. Now Kord Industries.
一天两起
That's two in one day.
12小时内两起
That's two in under 12 hours.
好吧  我要确保这是最后一起
Yeah, I'm gonna make sure it's the last one.
我不觉得那是你的  兄弟
I don't think that's yours, pal.
闪电侠
Flash.
你不觉得我想见见
You didn't think I'd want to come meet
铁山监狱的新囚犯吗
the newest resident of Iron Heights?
不  我想到了你会出现
No, I assumed that you'd show.
我只是没想到你会这么年轻
I just didn't expect you to be so young,
巴里·艾伦
Barry...Allen.
你怎么知道我是谁
Now, how do you know who I am?
我来自未来
I'm from the future.
你不相信  我想想  2017
You don't believe me? Let's see, uh, 2017.
你在劫难逃的爱人怎么样
How are things going with your doomed love,
爱瑞丝·韦斯特
Iris West?
还有你最强大的敌人  萨维塔
Or your greatest foe, Savitar?
你知道萨维塔
You know Savitar.
我知道关于他的一切  还有你
I know everything about him, and you.
什么...
What the--
吉普赛
Gypsy.
看样子还想复仇
Still seeking revenge, I see.
这次我会成功的
I'm gonna get it this time.
走着瞧
We'll see.
不
No!
魔术师
他自称为魔术师
He calls himself Abra Kadabra.
比如"嘛哩嘛哩哄"
As in hocus pocus?
显然他会很多把戏
He's certainly got a lot of tricks.
是  我们认为他体内植入了某种
Yeah, we think he has some sort of nanotechnology
纳米技术
built into his body--
给了他离奇的技能
allows him to do some extraordinary feats.
瞬间移动  心灵感应  多了去了
Teleportation, telekinesis, you name it,
相信我  我全见过
and believe me, I have seen it all.
所以他在巴里身上用的牌技
So that card trick he played on Barry,
斯塔格的水箱
the water tank at Stagg,
是他用魔术粉饰的未来科技吗
that's all some futuristic tech that he's masking as magic?
这是亚瑟·C·克拉克的第三定理
Well, it's Arthur C. Clarke's third law.
"足够先进的技术和魔术
"Any sufficiently advanced technology is...
并无二致"
indistinguishable from magic."
你来之前  他说他来自未来
Before you showed up, he said he was from the future.
未来
The future?
是的  64世纪
He is, 64th Century.
这下好  又一个来自未来的罪犯
Great, another criminal from the future.
这些人还不够我们受吗
Haven't we had our fill of those guys?
64世纪
64th Century.
你到底为什么要抓他
What exactly are you after him for?
他是回收者们的头号通缉犯之一
He's at the top of the collectors' most wanted list.
几年前出现在我的地球上
Showed up on my Earth a few years back,
几起抢劫造成了多人丧命
did a string of robberies that ended with a lot of people losing their lives.
几周前又出现了
Showed up again a couple weeks ago,
洗劫了几个科技公司  然后来了这
looted some tech companies, came here.
做同样的事  为什么
To do the same thing? Why?
他一定需要我们地球的技术达成目的
He must have needed our Earth's tech for something.
不管是什么  我们一定会帮你搞清楚
Well, whatever it is, we can definitely help you
我不知道你们是怎么想的
figure it out, 'cause I don't know about you guys,
但自从上次你来过之后
but ever since last time you were here,
我一直都期待着吉普赛的震波呢
I've been looking forward to some Gypsy vibe action.
-你太夸张了  -好丢人
- That's way too much. - Embarrassing.
我只是想抓到他  这样我就能
Yeah, I just want to catch him so I can bring his ass
把他送回地球十九关起来了
back to Earth-19 and put him down.
别担心  我们会帮你的
Don't worry. We can help you do that.
我们应该看看朱利安有没有发现
We should check and see if Julian's gotten anything.
我去问他
I'll go ask him.
在这期间  我们可以搞清楚
In the meantime, we can figure out
这个人消失去哪了
where this guy disappeared off to.
-给我搭把手呗  -智障
- Lend me a hand? - Stupid.
我认得这表情
I know that look.
你脑子里在想些什么呢
What is going on inside that head of yours?
这个人知道
This guy knew
你我会发生什么
what was going on with you and me
还知道萨维塔
and Savitar.
如果他知道关于萨维塔的事  那
If he knows something about Savitar, then--
他可能是救你的关键
He might be the key to saving you.
这是我们找到的第一条真正的线索
This is the first real lead we've gotten.
但是吉普赛呢
But, guys, what about Gypsy?
如果她抓到了那个人
I mean, if she gets ahold of him,
她会把他送回地球十九的
she's gonna take him back to Earth-19.
那个我们以后再说
We can figure that out later.
现在  我们要找到他
Right now, we just need to find him.
我什么也没发现
I got nothing.
为什么我找不到你呢
Why can't I find you?
我说过了  这人很聪明
I told you, this guy is smart.
你不能就这么震波魔术师的位置
You can't just vibe Kadabra's location.
无论他在做什么  我们都看不到他
Whatever he's doing, it renders him invisible to us.
好吧  如果我们不能震波他
Okay, well, if we can't vibe him,
那我想我们就得另寻他法了
then I guess we'll have to find him another way, right?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我在向尖端科研实验室卫星
I'm putting some search parameters
输入搜索参数
into the S.T.A.R. Labs satellite
看看有没有人的震动频率
to see if anybody vibrates at a different frequency
和地球一的人不一样
than Earth-1 folk.
真希望我们地球上也有这样的卫星
Wish we had a satellite that could do that on my Earth.
真希望我也有一套这科技
Wish I had a bunch of this stuff.
我可以帮你搞定  妹子
I could hook you up, girl.
这样吧  我去地球十九几天
How about this, I spend a few days on Earth-19,
给你搞一套最尖端的东西
and set you up with something state-of-the-art.
只不过呢
You know, the only thing is,
我需要个住的地方
I would need a place to crash, so.
-西斯科  -吉普赛
- Cisco-- - Gypsy.
那个吻  可不是
That kiss, that wasn't
吻别的吻
"I'll see you around".
那可是  还想快点再吻一次的吻
That was like, "That needs to happen again, real soon".
或者是我误解你了
Or did I misread that?
我一直都有事
I-I-I've been preoccupied.
只有那个原因吗
Is that the only reason?
时间掐得真好
Great timing!
水星实验室
看来大卫·科波菲尔[著名魔术师]离咱们不远
Looks like David Copperfield's not too far from us.
他在水星实验室的一处卫星办公室
He's at one of Mercury Labs' satellite offices.
又是一家科技公司吗
Another tech company?
最厉害的那家
The techiest.
带上那两个极速者  出发
Let's grab the speedsters and go.
哥们  你就是控制不住你自己吧
Man, you just can't help yourself, can you?
你这次带上了整支小队
You brought the whole team this time.
这可不怎么明智啊
That wasn't very smart, was it?
这人真烦
Oh, this guy sucks.
我知道你为什么这么想抓他了
I can see why you want to bring him down so badly.
为自己着想  放弃吧
Do yourself a favor, give it up.
你无处可逃了
There's nowhere for you to go.
你不可能同时骗过我们所有人  魔术师
You can't out-trick all of us, Kadabra.
我觉得我刚做到了
I think I just did.
这是全息影像
He's a hologram.
据进一步检测
Upon further inspection,
在斯塔格工业找到了一些
there was some rather odd particulate residue
很奇特的残渣
found at Stagg Industries.
那就是吉普赛之前说的纳米技术
Yeah, that's the nanotechnology that Gypsy was talking about.
但它的成分是什么
But what's it made out of?
还不清楚
Not exactly sure.
肯定是有机体  但好像
It's definitely organic, but it seems to have
又有某种金属氢的特性
some sort of metallic hydrogen properties.
老实说  这东西
Frankly, it's--
超出了你们的理解
Beyond your understanding.
不许动  否则你会后悔的
You make a move, you'll regret it.
你知道这话我听过多少次了吗  警探
Do you know how many times I've heard that, Detective?
我说了
Told you.
该死
Damn it.
跑  跑
Go, go, go!
大家躲到一边去
Guys, move to the side.
我现在能拿到我要找的东西
Now...I can get what I came for.
大家没事吧
Everybody okay?
无论是魔法还是科技  你都逃不掉
Magic or tech, doesn't matter. You're not getting out of these.
可能吧
Maybe not.
但如果你放我走  我就告诉你萨维塔最大的秘密
You let me go, I will tell you Savitar's greatest secret.
那是打败他  阻止他的关键
It's the key to defeating him, the key to stopping him.
什么秘密
What secret?
我知道他是谁
I know who he is.
我知道他的名字
I know his name.
把他交给我
Hand him over!
你们为什么把他关起来
Why'd you lock him up?
我要把他带回我的地球
I'm taking him right back to my Earth.
行  但我得先和他谈谈
Okay, but I need to talk to him first.
好吧  你尽管问他
Fine. Get what you need from him,
你一旦问完  就交给我
but when you're done, he's mine.
你将血债血偿
You are gonna die for all the things you've done.
我等不及要置你于死地了
I cannot wait to see you be put to death.
我去和她谈谈
Uh, I'm gonna talk to her.
吉普赛  宝贝
Gypsy, darling?
你说你知道萨维塔是谁
You said you know who Savitar is.
我了解极速之神的一切
I know everything about the God of Speed,
愿人都尊他的名为圣
hallowed be his name.
源自《圣经》马太福音第六章
说说看
Like what?
他无人能挡
That he's unstoppable,
他是第一位极速者
that he was the first speedster,
你打败了他
and that you defeat him,
但在那之前  他夺走了你最重要的东西
but not until after he takes what matters the most to you--
爱瑞丝·韦斯特
Iris West.
说他是谁  快
Tell us who he is, now!
我就不说
I don't think so.
很懊恼  对吧
It's frustrating, isn't it,
清楚自己要死
knowing that you're going to die
除非我给闪电侠他想要的
unless I give The Flash what he wants.
那样的力量  那样的速度
All that power, all that speed,
而你还是太慢了
and yet you're still too slow.
这不是游戏或把戏
This isn't a game or a trick.
这事关我女儿的性命
This is about my daughter's life.
这也事关我的性命
And it's my life
如果你们把我交给回收者
if you hand me over to that collector.
很简单
It's simple.
放我走  我告诉你们萨维塔是谁
Let me out, and I'll tell you who Savitar is.
把我交给吉普赛  爱瑞丝就会死
Give me to Gypsy, and Iris dies.
选择权在你手上  巴里
The decision lies with you, Barry.
各位  我们还不能让吉普赛带走他
Guys, we can't let Gypsy take him
我们得先找出萨维塔是谁
before we find out who Savitar is.
说得没错
No, we cannot.
那我们应该怎么做
Then what are we supposed to do?
我不知道
I don't know.
你和这家伙有什么纠葛
What is it with you and this guy?
你好像一条心要带他回去
It's like you're hell-bent on taking him back with you.
他在地球十九上杀了很多人
He killed a lot of people on Earth-19.
他也在这里杀过人
He's killed people here too.
他在这杀的人对你来说无足重轻
No one you know or care about.
他杀了你认识的人吗
Did he take somebody from you?
就是因为这个吗
Is that what this is about?
西斯科  重要的是
What this is about, Cisco,
我需要把他缉拿归案
is he needs to be brought to justice,
我不会让任何人或任何事
and I am not gonna let anything or anyone
阻止我
prevent me from doing that.
尖端科研实验室
你很走运
You're lucky.
你有可能伤得更重
This could've been a lot worse.
我没事  真的
I'm fine, really.
只是点皮肉伤
It's merely a flesh wound,
"巨蟒组"成员也是这么说的[英国六人喜剧团体]
as the "Monty Python" Boys would say.
不管怎样  谢谢你为我包扎
Anyway, thanks for patching me up.
小事情
Of course.
听着  我一直试着
Listen, I've been trying to find
找个合适的时机对你说这个...
the right time to say this, and...
现在似乎是个不错的时机
now seems to be as good a time as any.
我之前太过专注于不要令自己
I was so focused on not hurting you
变成冰霜杀手伤害到你
as Killer Frost
以至于我忘记了凯特琳·斯诺也会伤害到你
that I forgot that I could hurt you as Caitlin Snow,
对此我深表歉意
and for that I'm very sorry.
所以如果你不再相信我了我也能理解
So I understand if you don't trust me anymore,
但你能真心地原谅我吗
but... maybe you can find it in your heart to forgive me?
没事了  你可以走了
You're good to go.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们能想出办法的  巴里
We're gonna figure this out, Barry.
像魔术师这样的人
A guy like Kadabra,
他对你的生死没有发言权
he should have no say whether you live or die.
你怎么知道他说的是真的
How do you even know that he's telling the truth?
他来这除了耍魔术什么也没干
I mean, he's done nothing but tricks since he got here.
也许  也许这也是他耍的一个花招
I mean, maybe--maybe this is one of them.
不是的  爱瑞丝
It's not, Iris.
那...  你想放他走吗
So...what, you want to let him go?
感觉我们只能如此
I mean, it just feels like our only move.
他是个杀人犯
He's a murderer.
我知道他是个杀人犯
I know he's a murderer,
但我们把多少凶手关进监狱了
but I mean, how many murderers we put in prison?
我们打败了多少坏人了
How many bad guys have we taken down?
难道我们做了这么多
I mean, don't we deserve one win
就不能赢一次吗
after everything that we've done?
生活不是比赛  巴里
Life doesn't keep score, Barry.
你应该比任何人都知道这点
You should know that better than anyone.
即使魔术师还没有出现
Look, even if Kadabra hadn't showed up,
我们的生活还会是老样子
we'd still be in the same place we are right now.
但他出现了  如果他知道
But he did, and if he knows
萨维塔是谁  他会告诉我们的
who Savitar is, he's gonna tell us.
-巴里  -爱瑞丝  他能救你的命
- Barry-- - Iris, he can save your life.
不  救我的人是你
No, you can save my life.
不是他
Not him.
相信我
Trust me,
我也和你一样很想知道萨维塔是谁
I want to find out who Savitar is just as badly as you do.
但我不想让一个带来如此之多苦痛的人
But I don't want to let someone who has caused so much pain
为了救我而逍遥法外
walk free just to save my life.
我从心底里
You know, deep down,
觉得你也不想这样
I don't think you want that either.
我知道你会来的
I knew you'd come.
因为你是唯一一个什么都愿意做的人
'Cause you're the only person who's willing to do... anything.
你想要什么
What do you want?
自由
To be set free.
杀人  盗取智能科技
Murdering people, stealing smart tech.
你来这里是有目的的
You came here for something.
我说过了  警探
Told you before, Detective,
这已经超过了你的理解范围了
it is beyond your understanding.
这危及到我女儿的性命
This is about my daughter's life.
对我来说就是这么简单
It's as simple as that for me.
你告诉我萨维塔是谁
You tell me who Savitar is,
我就放你走
and I will let you go.
你不说的话  就和吉普赛一起离开吧
You don't, you're going with Gypsy.
对你我来说  这都是一个信心上的飞跃
A leap of faith for us both then.
打开门
Open the door.
如果你什么也不说就敢动
If you take one step before you tell me,
我会炸死你  明白了吗
I will blow you away. Understood?
但你确实不了解他
But you do not know this guy.
管道牢房警报
真是时候
Great timing!
那是什么
What is that?
不
No.
吉普赛
Gypsy!
告诉我名字
Give me the name.
快说名字
The name, now!
萨维塔  是
Savitar... is--
不  你在做什么
No! What the hell are you doing?
他正要告诉我萨维塔是谁
He was about to tell me who Savitar is!
靠
Damn it!
魔术师跑了  他就在楼里
Kadabra's on the loose! He's somewhere in the building!
终于拿到了
And there we are.
谢谢你  威尔斯医生
Thank you, Doctor Wells.
乔  他正走向电梯
Joe, he's headed for the elevator!
尖端科
研实验室
我们说好的
We had a deal.
用萨维塔的身份换你的自由
Your freedom for Savitar's identity.
我已经调整了我们的协议内容
I've altered the terms of our agreement.
你似乎也做了调整
It appears that you have as well.
快走
Move!
凯特琳  凯特琳  你还好吗
Caitlin! Caitlin, are you all right?
-你还好吗  -没事
- You all right? - Yeah.
-来吧  -我没事  我没事
- Come on. - I'm okay. Okay, I'm okay.
好了  好了  慢点  小心
Okay, okay, easy. Okay, easy.
-好了  -慢点  慢点
- Come on. - Gentle, gentle.
好了  好了
Yeah, yeah, yup.
那个  给我X光扫描仪
The-- the-- hand me the x-ray machine,
-请拿给我们  好吗  -好
- grab it for us, would you, please? - Yup.
给
Here, here.
很好  移开
Okay, good. Remove it.
有多严重
How bad is it?
很严重
Uh, it's bad.
很严重  你体内有一些碎弹片
It's bad, there's quite a few pieces of shrapnel inside you,
如果不马上取出
and they look deep enough to pierce your kidney
这种深度似乎可能刺穿肾脏
if they're not removed immediately.
大伙  我们得把她送到医院
Guys, we have to get her to a hospital.
不行  他们会认出她是超能力者
We can't, they're gonna ID her as a meta.
可不是普通的超能力者
And not just any meta.
对  是有过袭击中城警局存档的超能力者
Yeah, one that we have a file on for attacking CCPD.
那我们该怎么办  我们都不是医生
Then what are we going to do? None of us are doctors
她也不能给自己做手术
and she can't operate on herself.
我们还有一个选择
We do have another option.
什么
What is it?
凯特琳成为超能力者时  她的代谢率
When Caitlin goes meta, her metabolic rate
抵消了冷组织的破坏
offsets cold tissue destruction.
她可以再生
She can regenerate?
不  不能摘下我的项链
No, we're not gonna take off my necklace.
我不用去医院
I don't need a hospital.
我只需要一面镜子和稳健的双手
All I need is a mirror and a steady set of hands.
你在皇家陆军时是战地医生  对吧
You were a field medic in the Royal Army, right?
什么  不行  我从未给人动过手术
What? No, I-I-I've never operated on anyone before.
没关系  我来辅助你
That's okay, I'll walk you through it.
凯特琳  你说的是在手术期间
Caitlin, you're talking about staying awake
还要保持清醒
during your own surgery.
我把我的性命交给你了
I'm putting my life in your hands.
我相信你  朱利安
I trust you, Julian.
你到底在想什么
What the hell were you thinking?
现在不适合说这个  吉普赛
Now is not the time, Gypsy.
你这个警察的正义感真是莫名其妙
You know, you got a really messed up sense of justice for a cop?
说话小心点
Watch yourself.
我一生中发过两次誓
I took two oaths in my life.
一次是维护法律  一次是保护家人
One, to uphold the law. The other, to protect my family.
你猜哪个在我心中更重
Guess which one takes priority?
那是我的犯人
That was my prisoner.
他也曾是我的犯人 而你在我的地盘上
He was my prisoner too, and you're on my Earth.
他有能救爱瑞丝的消息
He has information that could save Iris's life,
其他的我才不管
so I don't give a damn!
就是因为你他才逍遥法外
It's because of you he's on the loose.
因为我  不  是因为你
Because of me? No, no, because of you.
是你打开了门  把他放了出去
You opened that door! You let him out!
都怪你  警探先生
That is on you, Detective!
你听到了多少
How much of that did you hear?
够多了
I heard enough.
那是我的朋友
This is my friend.
是他的女儿
It's the man's daughter.
你就不会为了在意的人做那样的事吗
I mean, wouldn't you do that for someone you cared about?
这正是我在做的  笨蛋
I am doing that, you idiot!
好吧  什么意思
Okay, what does that mean?
为了什么人  你在说谁
For who? Who are you talking about?
我曾经有位同伴
I used to have a partner.
你是指"伙伴"...还是伴侣
Like, a "Partne" or...like a partner?
都是
Both.
那是很久以前的事了  西斯科
It was a long time ago, Cisco.
我和他不是玩玩而已
It's not like I'm burning a candle for the guy, but
对我来说他真的很重要
he did mean something to me.
三年前  魔术师杀死了他
It's been three years since Abra Kadabra shot him dead.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
从那以后我就一直在找他
I have been searching for him ever since,
而他终于又现身了
and he finally showed back up.
十分钟前  我已经抓住他了
Ten minutes ago, I had him dead to rights,
然后你的朋友搞砸了一切
and then your friend messed it all up.
是的  我知道那种
So yes, I do know what it is like
太在意一个人所以打破规则的感觉
to care about someone so much that you break the rules.
这正是为什么我必须找到他  不惜一切
That's why I have to find this guy, no matter what,
等我成功了  我要让他付出代价
and when I do, he is gonna pay for what he did.
再不拖延
No more delays.
-准备好了吗  -好了好了
- Ready? - Ready as I'll ever be.
好  我们先清理表面的弹片
Okay, let's starst with the shrapnel on the surface.
好的
Okey-dokey.
如果我做错了什么
Just let me know if I do any
告诉我  好吗
...thing wrong, okay?
好  第一片  做得好
Okay, that's the first bit. Well done.
好了
Okay.
会流这么多血吗
Is there supposed to be this much blood?
弹片的确有可能在人体组织里
It's normal for the shrapnel to cavitate
割出空隙  但如果我失血过多
and displace tissue, but if I lose too much blood,
我会出现大出血症状
I'll start hemorrhaging.
好的
Okay.
我的天啊  好了
Oh, my God. Okay.
好了  就快好了  就快好了
All right, nearly done, nearly done,
坚持住  坚持住
hang in there, hang in there.
干得好  干得好  所有的...
Okay, well done. Well done, that's all the pieces
表面的弹片都清理干净了
of shrapnel from the surface gone.
很好  现在要处理最困难的部分了
Okay, great. Now it's time for the hard one.
但你做得很好
But you're doing great.
-你能做到的  朱利安  -好
- You got this, okay, Julian? - Yes.
它嵌在我的肾脏和下腔静脉之间
It's wedged between my kidney and my inferior vena cava,
周围都是一些大血管
and it's surrounded by some major blood vessels.
如果你碰到它们  很可能...
If you hit them, there's a good chance
-我会休克  -休克
- I'll go into shock. - Shock?
但没关系  你可以的
But it's okay. You've got this.
好的
Okay. All right.
心率上升了
Heart rate's increasing.
我觉得我夹住了
Okay, I think I've got it.
很好  往外拉
Great, pull it out.
我做不到  凯特琳  碎片卡住了
I can't, Caitlin, it's stuck.
那就换个方向
Then turn it.
伙计们  她的心跳加速到很危险的程度了
Guys, it's getting up there.
可能被一处肌腱挡住了
It might be a tendon in the way.
如果不是肌腱的话
If it's not a tendon--
那我就把你的项链拽掉
Then I will rip this necklace off.
不  那样我宁愿去死
No! I would rather die.
凯特琳  这一下会很疼
Caitlin, this is going to hurt.
能麻烦你给我进行缝合吗
Can you please stitch me up,
因为我觉得自己要昏过去了
because I think I need to pass out?
可以  当然没问题
Yes, yes. Of course, of course.
干得漂亮  干得漂亮
Well done, well done.
她会好起来的
She's gonna be all right.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
你刚刚真的棒极了  朱利安
That really was amazing, Julian.
货真价实  朱利安·艾伯特  医学博士
Seriously. Julian Albert, MD.
我觉得我搞清楚为什么魔术师
Hey, I think I know why Abra Kadabra's been
-要偷那些高科技零件了  -为什么
- stealing all that tech. - Why?
用来打造时间机器
Build a time machine.
他试图重返未来
He's trying to get back to the future.
瞧  成功了
Presto.
他手上拿着的那是什么东西
What is that thing in his hands?
魔术师窃取的所有东西
Everything Kadabra's been stealing,
都和我两年前用来建造邪恶威尔斯的
these are the exact components I used to build
时间球的部件完全一致
Evil Wells's time sphere two years ago,
但我一直没搞明白他用什么作为能量源
but I could never figure out what he used for a power source.
我觉得就是这玩意儿了
I think this is it.
所以这就是他从时间穹顶里偷走的东西吗
So that's what he took from the time vault,
时间球的能量源
its power source?
他返回64世纪所需的最后一块拼图
Last thing he needs to return to the 64th century.
那我们得在他
Well, we need to find his ass
再度消失前赶紧找到他的行踪
before he pulls another disappearing act.
如果魔术师的计划是让他自己
If Kadabra's plan is to "Marty McFly" himself
穿越回未来
back to the future--
他就必须先打开一个时光虫洞
He's gonna have to open a temporal wormhole first,
-而那时  -我们就能逮到他了
- and when he does-- - We can nail him.
不  他是我的
No, he's mine.
我非常期待让他体验我搭档当时
I look forward to showing him the same mercy
享受的同样待遇
he showed my partner.
吉普赛
Hey, Gypsy.
你不能一个人去追捕他
You can't go after him alone.
我当然能
Sure I can.
你想为被他伤害过的所有人以及你的搭档
You want justice for all those people that he's hurt,
讨回公道  对吗
for your partner, right?
现在我们在试图防止我们爱的人
Right now we're trying to prevent someone we love
受到伤害  但没你的帮助我们做不到
from getting hurt, but we can't do that without your help.
我现在信不过你们了
I don't trust you guys anymore.
魔术师已经从我们手中各逃脱过一次了
Kadabra's already given both of us the slip.
他现在又要通过穿越时间逃脱第三次
He does it again through time,
我不认为我们再会有这样逮住他的机会了
I don't think we get this opportunity back.
只有团结一心才能抓住他
Only way we catch him is together.
开始打开时光虫洞
伙计们  魔术师正顺着第九大道向南走
Guys, Abra Kadabra's heading south on Ninth.
他打开了一个时光虫洞
He opened up a wormhole.
你意下如何
What do you say?
我们不能让他穿越这道防线
We can't let him get past this.
我们不会让他得逞的
We're not gonna do that.
有本事你们就来抓我
Catch me if you can.
他现在在什么位置
Where's he at?
他现在在州立大道和主街交口
He's on State and Main!
交给我们吧
We're on it!
此路不通
You shall not pass!
好了  现在他在瑟洛街和第八大道交口
Okay, now he's on Thurlow and Eighth.
开火
-我们要跟丢他了  -不  不会的
- We're gonna lose him. - No, we're not.
他转到第七大道上了  速度很快
He's on Seventh, and he's moving fast!
你们得阻止这家伙
You gotta stop this guy.
开始打开
时光虫洞
该回家了
Time to go home.
巴仔  他又打开了一个虫洞
Bar, he opened up another wormhole!
太棒了  成功了  抓到他了
Yes! He did it, he got him.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
你玩消失的伎俩到此为止
So much for your disappearing act.
不
No!
根据地球十九的法律
By the laws of Earth-19, I hereby collect you
现以大屠杀罪名将你回收
for the crime of mass murder.
让她带走我吧
Let her take me.
你们永远不会知道我掌握的信息
You'll never find out what I know.
包括爱瑞丝之死
And Iris dies.
你们是来送我的吗
You've come to see me off.
感动死了
Really touched.
现在怎么办
What are we gonna do here?
你跟她走
You're going with her.
我不会阻拦她
I'm not gonna stop her.
那你就永远不会知道自己想知道的
Then you'll never find out what you want to know.
我没什么好跟你谈的
I have nothing to offer you.
没有缓刑
No reprieve.
没法逃避你该面对的惩罚
No escape for what you're facing.
你做的事罪大恶极
You've done some terrible things.
但你还算个人
But you are still a man.
你有家人
You have a family,
朋友和你在乎的人
friends, people that you care about.
你的内心深处肯定还有
Somewhere inside of you there must be
一丝人性的微光  一点希望
a glimmer of light, of hope.
我正是在请求内心深处的你
It's that part of you that I'm asking.
我恳求你
I'm begging.
帮我救救她
Help me save her.
闪电侠
Flash.
恳求
Begging.
听好了
See, here it is.
在未来  我和你是多年的老对头
In the future, you and I have been enemies for years.
当然你也有过其他敌人
Oh, there have been others, of course.
有斯旺  极速和迪沃
There was Thawne, Zoom, DeVoe,
但他们给你的伤害都不及萨维塔
but none of them hurt you like Savitar.
他让你彻底心碎
He truly broke you.
我得说实话
I have to be honest.
为此我总有点嫉妒
I was always a little bit jealous.
但现在就像我也有份杀了她
But now, it's like I get to kill her too.
失陪了  我得去接受刑罚了
If you'll excuse me, I have my execution to attend.
我们该何去何从
Where does this leave us?
不知道
I don't know.
西斯科  我
Cisco, I--
我还活着
I'm still here.
对
Yeah.
不会轻易放你走
Wasn't gonna let you go that easy.
魔术师
Kadabra?
他走了
He's gone.
显然再也不会回来了
He's gone for good, apparently.
抱歉  我手心出了好多汗
Sorry. My palm's are sweaty.
没关系的
It's quite all right.
老实讲  我的缝合技术
Honestly, my stitch work may leave
还有很多改进之处  所以
quite a lot to be desired, so.
没事
It's okay.
反正我也不是那种爱穿
I was never much of a two-piece bathing suit
两件式泳衣的姑娘
kind of gal anyway.
我很佩服你做的事  凯特琳
I cannot believe what you did, Caitlin.
清醒着做完了手术
I mean, staying awake during your own surgery,
这是其一  但期间还在指导我这双
that's one thing, but talking my clumsy hands
笨拙的手  真的太厉害了
through it, that's quite the other.
你勇气非凡
You are immensely brave.
你战胜了疼痛
You fought through the pain
这是我从未见识过的
like I've never seen anyone before.
艰难的活都是你做的
You did all the hard work.
很少
Hardly.
你对我心软了吗  朱利安
You going soft on me, Julian?
对
Yes.
绝对的
Absolutely.
我真的很抱歉
I'm so terribly sorry.
我真是笨手笨脚
That's most clumsy of me.
你还有一些陪护礼仪需要学习
Some bedside manner you got there.
我正在学习
I'm working on it.
好好休息
Just rest.
给你
Here you go.
谢谢
Thank you.
慢点
Easy.
抱歉
Sorry.
我本该更强势一点
I should've been stronger.
你觉得你应该朝魔术师开枪吗
You think you should've shot Kadabra?
爸  我觉得你放他走显示了真正的强大
Dad, I think you showed true strength by letting him go.
我为了你们尽力变得强大
I try to be strong for you guys,
为了你  沃利还有巴里
for you and Wally and Barry.
爸  你一直都是这样
Dad, you have been,
这也让我变得更强大
and it makes me stronger too.
当你很小的时候  我
When you were a baby, I was--
我很怕
I was terrified
你哪天夜里突然就死了
that you might die in the middle of the night.
我没法睡觉
I just didn't sleep.
我只能...
I would just...
守在你屋里...
sit in your room...
看你入眠
and watch you sleep.
我把手放在你胸前
I put my hand on your chest,
确保你还在呼吸  我...
just to make sure you were breathing, and then I--
只能坐在那里  祈祷...
I would just sit there there, praying that...
你能一直呼吸下去
you'd just keep breathing.
这就是我现在的感受
That's how I feel right now.
我不知道怎样做才能救你
I don't know what I can do to save you.
我知道怎样能救她
I know how to save her.
什么
What?
我知道怎样能救她
I know how to save her.
咒术师  萨维塔  斯旺
Kadabra, Savitar, Thawne.
他们总是比我们快一步
You know, they're always one step ahead of us...
因为一个原因
for one reason--
他们知道未来
they know what's gonna happen.
所以我们做出的每一个动作
So every move we make,
设置的每一个陷阱
every trap we try and set,
对他们而言不过是历史
it's all just history to them.
他们用未来武装自己
They're armed with the future.
但再也不会了
Well, not anymore.
什么意思
What does that mean?
如果我们需要阻止萨维塔和拯救你的答案
If the answers that we need to stop Savitar and save you
存在于未来  那我就需要去那里
are in the future, then that's where I need to go.
我要跑去未来
I'm gonna run to the future.
不许再吃草莓味的了
No more strawberry.
什么叫不许再吃草莓味的了
What do you mean, there's no more strawberry?
我只是一周前才买了一些
I just bought some, like, a week ago.
我可能吃了一些
Yeah, well, I may have eaten some,
或者说所有的
slash--all.
-西斯科  -你想让我出去
- Cisco. - Do you want me to go out
再帮你买一些草莓味的果冻吗
and get you more strawberry Jell-O?
我会再买一些
I will get you more.
不用了
No, it's fine,
但下次我给你做手术  你就什么也别想吃了
but next time I operate on you, you're getting bupkes, mister.
下次你给我做手术
Mm, next time you operate on me,
也许你可以治愈我破碎的心
maybe you can... fix my broken heart.
你和吉普赛没有成我很遗憾
I'm sorry it didn't work out with you and Gypsy.
如果来自不同宇宙但有着相同
If two meta-humans from two different universes
震波超能力的超能力者
with the same vibrational powers
都无法相恋  那还有什么希望呢
can't make it work, then what hope is there?
你们在这里呀
There you guys are.
我到处找...
I've been looking all over for--
你怎么躺在床上
what are you doing in bed?
说来话长  HR
It's a long story, H.R.
我也说来话长
I have a long story.
不如你告诉我们你去哪里了
Yeah, how about you tell us where you've been?
她叫朗达  她喜欢尝试新姿势
Her name is Rhonda, and she's into new positions.
-我们就...  -好了  天哪
- We had the-- - Okay. Oh, my God.
别说了  下次你决定去
Stop talking. You gotta let somebody know
风流两天时  先通知别人一声
next time you decide to go on a two-day love romp.
是谁在担心我  是他
Who was worried about me? He was.
我好感动
I'm touched.
下次你再做出这种事
You'll be touched in the face with a hammer
我就要用铁锤感动你一下
the next time you pull something like that.
伙计们  别闹了
Guys, stop it.
再逗我笑  我的伤口就要崩开了
Don't make me laugh, or I'll bust my stitches.
那是青柠果冻吗
Is that lime Jell-O?
都给你了  HR
It's all you, H.R.
你说真的吗
Are you serious?
我爱死青柠了
I... love the lime.
我爱青柠
I love the lime!
你真的有担心他  是吧
You were really worried about him, weren't you?
答应我  绝不能告诉他
Just promise me that you'll never ever tell him.
我发誓  否则不得好...
Cross my heart and hope to--
凯特琳
Caitlin?
凯特琳  凯特琳  来人啊
Caitlin? Caitlin? Somebody help!
怎么了  出什么事了
What happened? What happened?
不清楚  她突然开始抽搐了
I don't know, she just started seizing.
按住她  按住她
Hold her down, hold her down.
HR  按住她的腿  按住她
Hey, H.R., grab her legs. Hold her down!
怎么回事
What--what's happening?
-她没有呼吸了  -我们必须叫救护车
- She's not breathing. - We have to get an ambulance
-刻不容缓  -HR  去拿抢救器
- in here right now. - H.R., grab the crash cart.
西斯科  去拿氧气瓶
Cisco, grab the oxygen.
推过来
Wheel it over here!
平缓地  罩在她嘴上
Slow and steady, over her mouth.
好的
Okay, good.
来吧  平缓地  对  就这样
Come on, slow and steady, that's it.That's it.
怎么回事
What's happening?
她可能引起血凝了  我不确定
She may have threw a blood clot, I don't know.
-朱利安  -给电极板充电
- Julian! - Charge the paddles!
-好的  -把电极板给我
- Okay-- - Give me the paddles!
充电中  好了
Charging, you're good.
好  给我  放在这里  开始了
Okay, give me the-- give it here. Clear.
调到最大  一直到顶
All the way, turn it up to the top!
-调到最大  -好的  可以了
- All the way up! - Okay, you're ready.
-开始了  -开始了  注意远离
- Clear. - Clear, clear, clear.
充电  继续
Char--go.
她...
She's gotta--
加油  凯特琳  振作点
Come on, Caitlin, come on!
继续  继续
Keep going, just keep going.
给你  拿着这个
Uh, here, take this.
来吧  她快醒过来了
Here we go, she's coming back.
她快醒过来了
She's coming back.
她会的
Yes, she is.
加把劲  她会醒的
Come on. Here she comes.
加把劲  不要停止
Come on! Don't stop.
求你了
Please.
求你不要停止心跳
Please don't stop.
她走了
She's gone.
住手  那不是她想要的
Stop! That's not what she wanted!
我不管
I don't care!
我不要眼睁睁看着她死掉  好吗
I'm not gonna sit here and watch her die, okay?
好吗
Okay?
好了  朋友  没事了
It's all right, mate, it's okay.
没事了
It's okay.
凯特琳
Caitlin?